http://www.ifst.org/privacy

Skip to main content
About backHow we are run: our governance backAnnual General MeetingBoard minutes (BoT)Board of Trustees - ElectionsCommitteesOur backgroundProfessional conductMembership backNetworks and Communities backSpecial Interest Groups backSensory Science GroupFood Regulatory GroupFood Innovation (Product & Packaging) GroupFood Processing GroupFood Safety GroupFood Science and Nutrition GroupSustainability Steering GroupVolunteers' Advisory GroupHow to access IFST ForumsIFST Northern Ireland BranchIFST Scotland Branch backFood and Drink Reformulation for Health - February 2017IFST Lecture 2019: ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, Scotland, SSERCIFST Young Scientist Competition 2019 - ScotlandScience and the Parliament - 15 December 2017Science and the Parliament 2016Scottish Young Scientist of the Year - April 2017IFST Western Branch backIFST Young Scientist Competition 2019 - South of EnglandTo Hell & Back - The Story of HeavenlyNew ProfessionalsRegional BranchesStudents backStudent forumCompetitions and awardsFind your University RepresentativeKeep up to date with food newsMeet the Student GroupMeet the Student Group CommitteeNewsletter SpotlightPreparing for your career in foodCOVID-19 Advisory GroupFood Risk Management Systems Working GroupIFST North of England BranchProfessional Recognition backChartered ScientistRegister of Professional Food Auditors and Mentors backAuditor & Mentor requirementsOngoing registrationFields of operationHow to join the registerThe registerRegister of Professional Sensory Scientists backAm I eligible?How to applyCPD for Registered Sensory ScientistsRegistered ScientistRegister of Food Safety Professionals (RFSP) backChoosing the right level | RFSPProfessional Recognition for Food Safety ProfessionalsMembership levels backAssociate MembershipEligibility & CostsFellow (FIFST)Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs)Membership (MIFST)Student Associate MembershipNewsEvents backAbstracts and Speaker Biographies - IFST Sensory Science Group Event: Changing Perspectives in Sensory Science – Past, PresentAbstracts and Speaker Biographies - IFST Sensory Science Group event: 'Celebrating Individuality' -Application for a free student place: IFST Eastern Branch & UK:IE EHEDG Conference: 'Hygienic design in food processing environments'EU exit: Food and chemicals regulation – what can we expect? - speaker biographiesEastern Branch IFST Lecture Reception: ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, Quadram Institute, NorwichFood Authenticity and Traceability Breakfast Meeting - Speaker BiographyIFST Food Law Group event: 'Asking the right questions: theory and practice' - Speaker BiographiesIFST Food Risk Management Systems Webinar: Artificial Intelligence VideoIFST Food Science & Nutrition Group event: 'Sweeteners: The next level'
- Speaker BiographiesIFST Food Science and Nutrition Group event: "What is a 'pinch' of salt?" - speaker biographiesIFST Lecture 2019 - ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, Eastern Branch, Quadram Institute, Local Speaker BiographyIFST Lecture 2019 - ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, Scotland Branch, SSERC - Local Speaker BiographyIFST SC20 Webinar Series: Coronavirus: Food Safety Risk? Your Questions AnsweredIFST Sensory Science Group Webinar: Who needs AI when we have HI? - video recordingIFST Sensory Science Group event: 'Noel, Narrative & Numbers' Speakers BiographiesIFST Spring Conference (SC20): 'The appliance of food science' - Speaker BiographiesMichael MosleyNorthern Ireland Branch IFST Lecture Reception: ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, Moy Park, CraigavonScotland Branch IFST Lecture Reception: ‘Ultra-processed foods: The science and the policy’, SSERC, DunfermlineSpeaker Biographies - IFST Spring Conference 2019 (SC19): 'Nutritional Science over Gut Feel'Speaker Biographies and Abstracts - IFST Eastern Branch & UK:IE EHEDG Conference: 'Hygienic design in food processing environments'Test - IFST Team CPD event detailsWebinars backFood Innovation (Product & Packaging) Group WebinarsFood Processing Group WebinarsFood Regulatory Group WebinarsFood Safety Group WebinarsFood Science & Nutrition Group WebinarsProfessional Development WebinarsSC20 (Spring Conference) Box SetSensory Science Group WebinarsWorking Group WebinarsFor Organisations backAccreditation Schemes backAccreditation of degree courses backHow to apply for accreditation of a degree courseAccredited Degree ProgrammesSensory Training AccreditationShort Course Recognition SchemeConsultantsCorporate SupportersGroup SchemesGroup schemesManagement and LeadershipSafe and Local Supplier Approval (SALSA) backSALSA - HACCP trainingCareer Development backCareer InformationSubscription ratesWhat is CPD? backCPD for Chartered ScientistCPD standardsFive steps to perfect CPDmyCPD backmyCPD Online GuideStudent LaunchPad 2020Students & ApprenticesTerms of PaymentResources & Policy backCOVID-19 Knowledge Hub backConsumer information | COVID-19Coronavirus (COVID-19) - IFST Update | June 2020Education | COVID-19Nutrition and COVID-19 Myths | COVID-19 Knowledge HubCOVID-19 Knowledge Hub backGuidance for larger food operations | COVID-19Q&A for consumers | COVID-19 Knowledge HubQ&A for smaller food operations | COVID-19 Knowledge HubFood Science Facts backFood Science Fact SheetsPublications backInternational Journal of Food Science and TechnologyFood and Drink - Good Manufacturing Practice'IFST Advances in Food Science' book seriesFood Science and TechnologyFood and Drink - Good Manufacturing Practice: A Guide to its Responsible Management (6th edition), 2013Handbook of Microbiological Criteria for FoodsJournal of Food Processing and PreservationScience and Policy Resources backFAN’s Monthly Highlights PlusPlastic Packaging in the Food and Drink IndustryScience In ParliamentSustainability seriesSustainable Food SystemCOVID-19 Knowledge Hub
Log in
Privacy
Introduction
Your privacy is important to us.
We collect personal information by lawful and fair means and, where appropriate, with your knowledge or consent.
Before or at the time of collecting personal information, we will identify the purposes for which information is being collected.
We collect and use personal information solely for fulfilling those purposes specified below unless we obtain your consent or as required by law.
We process your personal data within the European Union. Third party service providers acting on our behalf may store your personal data on systems outside of the EU. If that is the case, we will take technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data and ensure an equivalent level of safeguard.
Types of personal information we collect
We may collect your name, postal address, email address, telephone number to identify and communicate with you.
We may collect information about your education and qualifications, extent and number of years’ experience, and employment history for the purposes of assessing your suitability for membership and registration.
We may collect gender, date of birth, and other characteristics to measure the effectiveness of our equal opportunity policies.
If you visit our websites, your computer type, operating system, length of visit, page views and browsing habits (including your Internet Protocol (‘IP’) address, geographical location, browser address and other information relating to your visit) may be tracked (we may use cookies) to enable us to monitor traffic and make improvements to our websites.
Purpose for collecting personal information
We use your personal data to keep you updated with relevant information which forms part of your package of services and/or membership benefits, and in pursuit of our charitable object, which is the general advancement and application of food science and technology, for the benefit, safety and health of the public.
Our communications with you may be by post, telephone or e-mail, and may originate from IFST or our regional branches and subject interest groups. Visitors to our web sites may receive communications via their own personal area on the sites.
We use your personal data to arrange for the distribution of IFST publications.
We will not pass on your details to unrelated third-parties unless you specifically opt-in to this type of communication.
We may publish some details (your name, category of membership or registration, and date membership/registration granted - but never your contact details) of members in our publications and on our website. Our publications are sent to members worldwide and may be bought by non-members e.g. university libraries. There is also unrestricted access to our websites.
You may opt-out of receiving a chosen communication at any time by following the unsubscribe directions provided (if appropriate), by updating your contact preferences on our websites or by contacting us (email or write to us at the address below).
Legal bases of processing personal information
We collect and process personal information with your consent (GDPR 6(1)(a)), because processing is necessary for the performance of a contract (6(1)(b)), because the processing is necessary for the performance of task carried out in the public interest (6(1)(e), or because the processing is necessary for the purposes of legitimate interests (6(1)(f)).
Who has access to your personal data and to whom is it disclosed?
We may disclose information about you to any of our team (employees and volunteers), suppliers or subcontractors (such as the publishers of IFST publications or our accountants) as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy.
In addition, we may disclose your personal information:
To the extent we are required to by law;
In connection with any legal proceedings;
In order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.
Your personal information may only be shared with good reason as follows:
Assessors will be given access to information necessary to assess your application for membership, registration or revalidation;
Employers or potential employers, on request, will receive confirmation of your membership or registration status;
Our regions and interest groups may be given access to information necessary to provide you with local, personalised service;
If registered on a Science Council register (as a Chartered Scientist, Registered Scientist, Registered Science Technician) your name, registration award, membership and registration status, registrant ID and other information to correctly identify you will be shared with the Science Council;
If registered on one of IFST’s registers, such as the Register of Professional Food Auditors and Mentors or the Register of Food Safety Professionals, your name, registration number and fields of operation, or level of registration may be published on our websites.
How do we protect and safeguard your information?
We will protect personal information by using reasonable security safeguards against loss or theft, as well as unauthorised access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.
Our employees and, where relevant, volunteers (including assessors) receive training in data protection and are bound by IFST policies.
How can you verify, modify or delete your information?
We aim to ensure that the information we hold is as accurate as possible. We may contact you periodically to ensure the data we hold is complete, accurate and up to date. We encourage you to update us of any changes.
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the address below. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, please write to us at the address below.
How long do we keep your personal data?
We will only retain personal information for as long as necessary for the fulfilment of the purposes stated above.
We do not hold more information than we need to provide your package of services or membership benefits, or in pursuit of our charitable object. We may ask you for information to inform our policy work, such as reporting on the nature of the food science workforce.
We do not hold your data longer than we need to. For applicants, current members and registrants this is a lifetime record, which extends to a maximum two years post-mortem. For former members and registrants, records are reviewed annually and normally destroyed or anonymised after six years of inactivity. For all other contacts, records are reviewed annually and normally destroyed or anonymised after two years of inactivity.
Contact information
We are committed to and carry out our business in accordance with data protection principles. If, for whatever reason, you wish to comment or raise a concern, please write to our Honorary Treasurer, who is responsible for data protection matters on behalf of the Board:
Hon. TreasurerInstitute of Food Science and Technology5 Cambridge Court210 Shepherds Bush RoadLondon W6 7NJ
info@ifst.org
Our websites use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but you can normally modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Links to other websites
Our website contains links to other websites. We do not have any control over other websites and we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide whilst visiting such sites; such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the websites in question.
If you interact with us usuing social media forums like Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram, LinkedIn, Youtube, etc., please use the tools provided by those sites to make choices about how you share your personal data in your social media profile(s).
Social Media
The social media platforms and pages of Institute of Food Science and Technology (IFST) are listed below and on https://www.ifst.org/ . They are intended for informational and promotional purposes.
Twitter
LinkedIn
Instagram
Facebook
Any content, views, opinions and/or responses to questions uploaded, expressed or submitted by users, other than the content provided by IFST, are solely the views, opinions and responsibility of the person submitting them and do not necessarily reflect the opinions of IFST. IFST is not responsible for content that third parties publish, post, upload, distribute, disseminate or otherwise transmit via the social media accounts created by IFST.
We may share links to other web pages, but these links are not an endorsement of those pages. Similarly, any interactions such as likes, retweets and follows are not an endorsement to those accounts. IFST is not responsible for the content of any website or social media platform not operated by IFST, nor accounts claiming to be IFST.
IFST does not warrant the accuracy, completeness or usefulness of the information available in its social media channels. Nothing contained in or provided through these online channels is intended to constitute advice. Any reliance you place on such information is strictly at your own risk.
We strongly advise you to protect your identity: do not publish any personal data on our page. These include telephone numbers, email addresses, or any other personal information. If you need to send us these details, please contact us via email info@ifst.org.
More information
We are registered as a data controller with the Information Commissioner. Our registration can be found on the Information Commissioner's Office website:
https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/what-we-do/register-of-data-controllers/
